A Guide to the Papers of the Secretary of the Board of Visitors of the University of Virginia, 1945-1997
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Secretary of the Board of Visitors of the University of Virginia 1945-1997
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-1/2/1.002
This collection consists of 6,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
For ten years from the date of creation, access to these records will be granted only under the procedures of the Virginia Freedom of Information Act (Code of Virginia -2.1-340 ff.) or with the specific permission of the Secretary of the Board. Researchers interested in obtaining access to these records should direct a request in writing to the Office of the Legal Adviser, Madison Hall, University of Virginia.
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred by Jeanne F. Bailes, Clerk of the Board of Visitors, Office of the Board of Visitors, The Rotunda, University of Virginia on 2000 December 4.
Biographical/Historical Information
During the time span of these papers, Raymond C. Bice,Jr. (1969-1990) and Alexander G. Gilliam, Jr. (1991- ) both held the position of Secretary to the Board of Visitors.
Scope and Content Information
The papers consist of general records of the Secretary, including correspondence, memoranda, and related papers.
Contents List
- AAU Institutions 1984-1988 (Box 1)
- Academic Computing 1987 (Box 1)
- Administration, Vice President for 1984-1986 (Box 1)
- Administrative Authority, Order of 1970 (Box 1)
- Administrative Review 1981 Nov 20 (Box 1)
- Admissions 1989-1992 (Box 1)
- African-American Affairs Office 1976-1993 (Box 1)
- Alderman Library 1986-1993 (Box 1)
- Alumni Association 1945-1992 (Box 1)
- Alumni Patents Foundation 1981 (Box 1)
- Association of Governing Board 1990-1992 (Box 1)
- Athletic Report 1969 Jul 1-1970 Jun 30 (Box 1)
- Athletics (2 folders) 1969-1990 (Box 1)
- Athletic Programs, Intercollegiate 1992 June 30 (Box 1)
- Audit Department 1989-1993 (Box 1)
- Birdwood 1971-1984 (Box 1)
- Board of Visitors-General 1980-1994, (2 folders) (Box 1)
- Board Meetings-Regular 1977-1984 (Box 2)
- Board Meetings-Open, General 1979 (Box 2)
- Board Meetings-Open, Correspondence to News Media re: 1979 (Box 2)
- Board Meetings Executive Session 1980-1988 (Box 2)
- Board Meetings-Open 1987-1989 (Box 2)
- Board Meetings-Executive Session 1989-1992 (Box 2)
- Board Meetings-Open 1990, (1 of 2 folders) (Box 2)
- Board Meetings-Open 1990, (2 of 2 folders) (Box 3)
- Board Meetings-Open 1991, (2 folders) (Box 3)
- Board Meetings-Open 1992-1993 (Box 3)
- Board Meetings-Open 1993 (Box 4)
- Board Meetings-Open 1994, (2 folders) (Box 4)
- Board Meetings-Open (1 of 3) 1995 (Box 4)
- Board Meetings Open (2 of 3) 1995 (Box 5)
- Boar's Head Inn 1969-1988 (Box 5)
- Budget 1990-1993, (2 folders) (Box 5)
- Bursar's Office 1981-1987 (Box 5)
- Calendar and Scheduling 1960-1962 (Box 5)
- Called Meetings 1965-1973 (Box 5)
- Campaign for UVA, Briefing of the Former and Current Members of the Board of Visitors 1994 Jun (Box 5)
- Certifications 1985-1989 (Box 5)
- Clinch Valley College Advisory Board 1986-1988 (Box 5)
- College of Arts and Sciences 1971-1987 (Box 5)
- Comptroller, University 1968-1993 (Box 5)
- Continuing Education 1987-1996 (Box 5)
- Council of Presidents 1971-1973 (Box 6)
- Council of Visitors 1976-1985 (Box 6)
- Development 1988-1990 (Box 6)
- Docket, Preparation of 1986-1993 (Box 6)
- Docket, Preparation 1993-1994 (Box 6)
- Employment Benefits 1961-1975 (Box 6)
- Endowment Review 1988 May 10-11 (Box 6)
- Equal Opportunity 1987-1994 (Box 6)
- Executive Vice-President, Office of the-Planning for 1979-1985 1979 Sep 15 (Box 6)
- Facilities Management 1987-1993 (Box 6)
- Facilities Management/Physical Plant 1988 (Box 6)
- Faculty Housing 1980-1988 (Box 7)
- Faculty Senate 1973-1992 (Box 7)
- Faculty Seniority List 1968 (Box 7)
- Fees 1990-1991 (Box 7)
- Freedom of Information 1973-1982, (2 folders) (Box 7)
- Former Members of the Board 1968-1989 (Box 7)
- Former Members of the Board of Visitors 1989-1996, (5 folders) (Box 8)
- Gardner, Carroll (Jerry) 1970-1974 (Box 8)
- General Council 1989-1994, (2 folders) (Box 8)
- Gifts 1987-1993 (Box 9)
- Governor's Office 1971-1994 (Box 9)
- Graphics 1989-1990 (Box 9)
- Grattan IV, Mr. George G. 1974-1988 (Box 9)
- Gross, Paul R. 1986 (Box 9)
- Haas, Raymond M. 1982-1988 (Box 9)
- Historic Central Grounds 1975-1984 (Box 9)
- Hospital 1984-1992 (Box 9)
- Human Resources 1986-1995, (3 folders) (Box 9)
- Hunt, Ray C. JR 1981-1988 (Box 9)
- Jefferson's Scholars Program 1988-1992 (Box 9)
- Material Management 1984-1993, (2 folders) (Box 9)
- Medicine, School of 1980-1985 (Box 9)
- Medical Center Council of Trustees-Minutes 1977-1984 (Box 10)
- Membership Directory 1960-1984 (Box 10)
- Memoranda to the Board of Visitors 1988-1990, (4 folders) (Box 10)
- Memoranda to the Board of Visitors 1991-1992, (3 folders) (Box 11)
- Memoranda to the Board of Visitors (1 of 2) 1992 Jul-Dec (Box 11)
- Memoranda to the Board of Visitors (2 of 2) 1992 Jul-Dec (Box 12)
- Memoranda to the Board of Visitors 1993 Jan-Jun, (2 folders) (Box 12)
- Memoranda to the Board of Visitors (1-2 of 3) 1993-1994 (Box 12)
- Memoranda to the Board of Visitors (3 of 3) 1993-1994 (Box 13)
- Memoranda to the Board of Visitors 1994 (Box 13)
- Minutes (Excerpts from) 1971 (Box 13)
- Minutes-Public 1984 (Box 13)
- Minutes-Correspondence 1990-1992 (Box 13)
- Miscellaneous 1969-1988, (2 folders) (Box 13)
- Named Professorships 1988-1992 (Box 14)
- Named Professorships & Endowed Chairs 1993-1994 (Box 14)
- Named Professorships and Endowed Chairs 1995-1997 (Box 14)
- NCAA 1993 (Box 14)
- News Clips 1991-1992, (2 folders) (Box 14)
- Newspaper clippings 1992 (Box 14)
- News Clippings 1993 (Box 15)
- Newspaper Clippings 1993-1994 (Box 15)
- Newspaper Clippings 1994-1995, (2 of 3 Folders) (Box 15)
- Newspaper Clippings 1994-1995, (3 of 3 Folders) (Box 16)
- Newspaper Clippings 1995-1997, (3 Folders) (Box 16)
- News Release Policy 1970 (Box 17)
- Nursing, School of 1972-1982 (Box 17)
- Orientation of New Board Members 1966-1988 (Box 17)
- Parking 1969-1984 (Box 17)
- Petty Cash Fund 1967-1993 (Box 17)
- Preliminary Meeting of the Board 1992-1995 (Box 17)
- President's Memoranda (Miscellaneous) 1974-1990 (Box 17)
- Project Status Report 1989-1991 (Box 17)
- Resolution, Petition and Supporting Documents of the Student Bar Association of the University of Virginia School of Law Urging Responsible Divestment of the University's Investments in South Africa 1985 Oct 11 (Box 17)
- Resource and Policy Studies, Office of 1969-1981 (Box 17)
- Risk Management and Safety 1980-1988 (Box 17)
- Salaries 1968-1988 (Box 17)
- Salaries 1986-1988 (Box 17)
- Sponsored Programs 1973-1995 (Box 17)
- State Council of Higher Education 1971-1992 (Box 17)
- Student Affairs 1980-1984 (Box 17)
- Student Council 1980-1987 (Box 18)
- Tickler File 1970-1975 (Box 18)
- University Press 1963-1992 (Box 18)
- Voice Communications 1988-1991 (Box 18)
- Yarmolinsky Visit 1993 (Box 18)